Guide to the Alexander Sprunt and Son Records, 1779-1960 RL.10194
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Volumes, 1890s-1950s
  - Cotton
    - Personal Cotton Book, 1891-1893 (Volume 115A)
    - Cotton Receipts, 1893 Dec.-1895 Aug. (Volume 116)
    - Record of Cottone Purchases, 1920 Mar.-1926 Dec. (Volume 117)
    - Record of Cotton Purchases, 1933 May-1935 Nov. (Volume 118)
    - Cotton Receipts by Railroad, 1925 (Volume 119)
    - Register of Cotton Buyers (including shipping records of Champion Compress and Warehouse Co.), 1897-1921 (Volume 120)
    - Invoices Examined, 1897 Dec.-1900 Oct. (Volume 121)
    - Invoice Outturns, 1934-1936 (Volume 122)
    - Cotton Purchases and Sales (Wilson, Maxton, Smithfield, Clinton, Roseboro, Tarboro, Rocky Mount, Dunn), 1933-1934 (Volume 123)
    - Cotton Storage: Clinton, 1933-1934 (Volume 124)
    - Cotton Storage: Maxton, 1933 Sept. (Volume 125)
    - Cotton Storage: Smithfield, Dunn, Goldsboro, 1933-1934 (Volume 126)
    - Cotton Futures Purchases and Sales, 1940-1949 (Volume 127)
  - Stock
    - Daily Market Position, 1939 Aug.-1940 May (Volume 128)
    - Stock Inventory, 1895 Sept.-1901 Aug. (Volume 129)
    - Stock Inventory, 1901 Sept.-1912 Mar. (Volume 130)
    - Stock Inventory, 1911 May-1918 Feb. (Volume 131)
    - Stock Inventory, 1918 Feb.-1920 Nov. (Volume 132)
    - Stock Inventory, 1920 Nov.-1922 Dec. (Volume 133)
    - Stock Inventory, 1925 Aug.-1928 Sept. (Volume 134)
    - Stock Inventory, 1931-1933 (Volume 135)
    - Stock Inventory, 1935 Mar.-Jul. (Volume 136)
    - Stock Record, 1936-1937 (Volume 137)
  - Shipping and Sales
    - Daily Stick Sheets, 1920 Apr.-1923 Dec. (Volume 138)
    - Consignment Receiving Register, 1901 Nov.-1902 Oct. (Volume 139)
    - Invoice or Account Sales Ledger, 1893-1895 (Box 140, Volume 140)
    - Sales Record, 1914-1915 (Volume 141)
    - Sales Contracts, 1923-1924 (Volume 142)
    - Sales Confirmations, 1926 Dec.-1928 (Volume 143)
    - Register of Ships and Cargoes, 1897-1915 (Volume 144)
    - Steamer Charters, 1905-1918 (Volume 144A)
    - Shipping Invoice Register, 1895 (Volume 145)
    - Shipping Invoice Register, 1903 Sept.-1908 May (Volume 146)
    - Shipping Book, 1906 Sept.-1907 Sept. (Volume 147)
    - Foreign Currency Ledger, 1919-1924 (Volume 148)
    - Fertilizer Sales Book, 1881-1884 (Volume 149)
  - Champion Compress and Warehouse Company
    This stock company was organized in 1878 and was the third cotton compress in Wilmington. It continued to function into the 1950s either as an independent firm or as part of Alexander Sprunt and Son, and it was chartered, rechartered, and dissolved several times. Company documents can be found in the following Office Files: No. 6010, No. 6023, and No. 7306. The purchase by the Sprunts of the firm's entire capital stock was noted in the Private Letterpress Book, 1893 (pg. 9). The surrender of the company's charter in 1946 was noted in the profit and loss account of Ledger of June-Sept. 1946. Operations and physical plant are illustrated in the Pictures Series. A guano warehouse was maintained so that the fertilizer was a significant part of the business in addition to cotton.
    - Minutes of the Meetings of the Stockholders and the Board of Directors, 1878-1911 (Volume 150)
    - Ledger B, 1889-1905 (Volume 151)
    - Ledger, 1930-1933 (Volume 152)
    - Ledger, 1933-1937 (Volume 153)
    - Ledger, 1937-1940 (Volume 154)
    - Ledger, 1940-1942 (Volume 155)
    - Ledger, 1942-1944 (Volume 156)
    - Ledger, 1945-1946 (Volume 157)
    - Ledger, 1946 Jun.-Sept. (Volume 158)
    - Ledger, 1946-1953 (Volume 159)
    - Stock Inventory, 1899 Sept.-1901 Aug. (Volume 160)
    - Cotton Storage, 1954-1955 (Volume 160A)
    - Tobacco Storage, 1954-1955 (Volume 160B)
    - Tobacco Storage, 1955-1956 (Volume 160C)
    - Tobacco Storage, 1955-1956 (Volume 160D)
  - Wilmington Compress and Warehouse Company
    This company was owned by Alexander Sprunt and Son and appears as an asset in its financial statement of Aug. 31, 1915 (Office File 6028). The extent, nature, and duration of this ownership is not clear. The stock company was the second cotton compress established in Wilmington (1875), the first having been operated by the Confederate government (1864-1865). This information is found in James Sprunt's Information and Statistics Respecting Wilmington, N.C. (Wilmington, N.C.), pg. 143-144.
    - Ledger A, 1875-1893 (Volume 161)
    - Ledger B, 1893-1910 (Volume 162)
    - Cashbook A (there is no Cashbook B), 1875-1893 (Volume 162A)
    - Cashbook C, 1893-1907 (Volume 163)
    - Cashbook D, 1907-1910 (Volume 164)
    - Cash Journal, 1925 May-Jun. (Volume 165)
  - Dalziel Cotton Warehouse Company
    This company was organized in 1916 at Charlotte as the Sprunt-Charlotte Warehouse Company in which Walter P. Sprunt held 247 of 250 shares of capital stock ($25000). In 1918, the firm's name was changed to the Dalziel Cotton Warehouse Company which it remained until dissolution in 1927. The capital stock was soon transferred to business associates of the Sprunts. The latter owned the warehouse building and carried an account in their ledger for the same amount as the capital stock of the Dalziel Company.
    - Minutes of the Stockholders and of the Board of Directors, 1916-1927 (Volume 166)
      Including financial statements, ledger of 1916-1917, stockholders' ledger, and register of original and re-issued stock certificates.
    - New York Office: Trial Balance Book No. 1, 1917 Jul.-1919 Nov. (Volume 167)
      Includes Cotton Future Contracts Traded, 1916-1924.
    - New York Office: Cash Journal, 1920 Oct.-1922 Dec. (Volume 168)
    - New York Office: Futures Cashbook, 1922-1929 (Volume 169)
    - New York Office: Futures Cashbook, 1930 (Volume 170)
    - Cotton Futures Purchases and Sales, 1921-1924 (Volume 171)
    - Cotton Futures Purchases and Sales, 1924-1930 (Volume 172)
    - Cotton Futures Purchases and Sales, 1930-1931 (Volume 173)
  - The Sprunt Corporation and Alexander Sprunt and Son, Inc., Delaware
    See Office File 6545 for minutes and other papers, 1931-1937.
    - Ledger, 1931-1937 (Volume 174)
    - Ledger, 1941-1942 (Volume 175)
    - Ledger, 1942-1943 (Volume 176)
    - Ledger, 1943-1944 (Volume 177)
    - Ledger, 1944-1945 (Volume 178)
    - Ledger, 1945-1946 (Volume 179)
    - Ledger, 1946-1947 (Volume 180)
    - Ledger, 1948-1949 (Volume 181)
    - Ledger, 1948-1953 (Volume 182)
    - Charlotte Branch Letter Book: H-K, 1930-1933 (Volume 183)
    - Charlotte Branch Ledger, 1915-1917 (Volume 184)
    - Charlotte Branch Cotton Received and Shipped, 1916 Oct.-1922 Oct. (Volume 185)
      Includes negotiable receipts, 1916 Nov.-1922 Oct.
    - Boston Branch Cashbook, 1909 Aug.-1920 Apr. (Volume 186)
    - Dothan Branch Ledger, 1932-1934 (Volume 187)
    - Dothan Branch Call and Cotton Purchases Journal, 1932-1934 (Volume 188)
    - Bremen Branch Letter Book, 1909 Jun.-1911 Sept. (Volume 189)
      Especially Frederick Huth and Co. and German Bank of London.
    - Bremen Branch Letter Book, 1909 Jun.-1913 Mar. (Volume 190)
      Especially Konig Brothers, London.
    - Bremen Branch Letter Book, 1910 Jun.-1911 Mar. (Volume 191)
      Especially Deutsche Nationalbank, Bremen.
    - Bremen Branch Letter Book, 1911 Oct.-1914 Mar. (Volume 192)
      Especially Frederick Huth and Co. and German Bank of London. See Office File 7323 for profit and loss statement of 1909.
    - Le Havre Branch Ledger, 1911-1912 (Volume 193)
    - Le Havre Branch Ledger Index, 1911-1912 (Volume 194)
    - Le Havre Branch Ledger No. 1, 1912-1913 (Volume 195)
    - Le Havre Branch Ledger No. 1 Index, 1912-1913 (Volume 196)
    - Le Havre Branch Ledger No. 2, 1913-1914 (Volume 197)
    - Le Havre Branch Ledger No. 3, 1914-1915 (Volume 198)
    - Le Havre Branch No. 3 Index, 1914-1915 (Volume 199)
    - Le Havre Branch Ledger No. 4, 1915-1916 (Volume 200)
    - Le Havre Branch Journal, 1913 Sept.-1914 Nov. (Volume 201)
    - Le Havre Branch Journal, 1914 Nov.-1915 Nov. (Volume 202)
    - Le Havre Branch Journal, 1915 Nov.-1916 Sept. (Volume 203)
    - Le Havre Branch Journal, 1916 Sept.-1917 Jun. (Volume 204)
    - Le Havre Branch Journal, 1918 Apr.-1919 Sept. (Volume 205)
    - Highland Farms Journal, 1924-1925 (Volume 206)